Guide to the Robert Triffin Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Robert Triffin papers
1934-1978
MS 874
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
38.5
(39 boxes)
Correspondence, reports, writings, lectures, and clippings relating to Robert Triffin's career as an economist and professor of economics at Yale University, including material on European monetary systems and banking, and financial missions around the world.
Triffin, Robert
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Robert Triffin, 1979.
Arrangement
Arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of subject files with a limited amount of correspondence, confidential reports mimeographed for limited distribution, printed material on economic development of various foreign countries, carbon typescripts of writings, articles and lectures, research material, and unpublished manuscripts by Triffin, and press clipping files. Files on courses taught at Yale are also present, and some include original material from the subject files which have been filed in with the course material. The presence of a significant amount of correspondence within a folder has been noted whenever possible in the inventory.
Subject files are relative to the financial integration of Europe centering on monetary systems and banking. Of particular interest is the material concerning the economic reconstruction of Europe after W.W.II, which includes reports on the economic penetration of the Germans into the financial structures of occupied countries, including those in Eastern Europe. (See Boxes 24-26). Main topics include: International Monetary Fund, European Payments Union, European Economic Community, O.E.E.C, international liquidity and monetary reform, economic conditions in Europe and Latin America, problems with the U.S. dollar, gold and sterling, exchange rates and the unit of account. Files on Triffin's financial missions abroad for the U.S. government are divided by country. They cover Missions to Latin America, Missions to Western Europe and Japan. The Mission to Iran is well documented and includes folders on the nationalization of the oil industry and the oil negotiations, 1951-1952. Also present are the files on the ECAFE Missions to Asia on the Asian Payments Union. Beginning as almost a complete folder by folder listing, the preliminary inventory grows more general after Box 20. The material in the last boxes arrived in a less organized state and should be checked by researchers if it bears upon their topic. Little rearrangement of the contents of the papers has been done.
Biographical / Historical
Robert Triffin (1911-): born in Belgium; M.A., Harvard, 1938, Ph.D., 1939; instructor in economics, Harvard, 1939-1942; chief Latin Am. sect. bd. of govs., Fed. Res. System, 1942-1946; dir. exchange control div., IMF, 1946-1948, head tech. rep. in Europe, 1948-1949; prof. economics, Yale, 1951-1958, Pelatiah Perit Prof. Pol. & Soc. Sci., 1957-1967, Frederick Wm. Beinecke Prof. Economics 1967-1979, emeritus, 1979-
Banks and banking, International; Economics -- Study and teaching; International finance; World War, 1939-1945 -- Economic aspects; European Economic Community countries -- Economic conditions; Iran -- Economic conditions -- 1945-1979; Economists; Educators; Triffin, Robert; Yale University -- Faculty
- Inventory, [1934-1978]; 35; (35 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Received: 1/12/79 from Yale Economics Department
  - Private studies on International Liquidity and Monetary Reform
    - Dossier Robert Triffin, Problèmes Monétaire Internationaux (Box 1)
  - Basic documents on International Liquidity and Monetary Reform
    - International Monetary Reform, International Monetary Fund (IMF) (Box 1)
    - Continental European Views: EEC (Box 1)
    - Secret File of Ten (Groupe des Dix or Group of Ten) (Box 1)
    - France (Box 1)
    - EEC Countries (except France) (Box 1)
    - United States views:
      - Treasury: Dillon and Roosa (Box 1)
      - Council of Economic Advisers and Tobin (Box 1)
      - Berstein (Box 1)
    - DeGaulle and Giscard speeches, 1965 February (Box 1)
    - British views: Wilson, Maudling, Harrod, Tew (Box 1)
    - Commodity Reserve Plan (Box 1)
    - Continental views:
      - Holtrop (Box 1)
      - Posthuma (Box 1)
      - Emminger and Blessing (Box 1)
    - Technical papers: Gilbert, Emminger, Machly, Despres, Mundell, Keiland, C.E.D. (Box 1)
      General
      See also: U.S. views, Bernstein
    - Latin American countries (Box 2)
  - Press clippings on International Monetary Reform and Triffin
    - Reprints, by author
      - A (Box 2)
      - B to F (Box 2)
      - G to K (Box 2)
      - L to P (Box 2)
      - Q to U (Box 2)
      - V to Z (Box 2)
    - Money cranks (Box 2)
    - Newspaper clippings (Triffin)
      - 1965 (U.S.) (Box 2)
      - American (Box 2)
      - French (Box 2)
      - German (Box 2)
      - United Kingdom (Box 2)
      - Other (Western Europe) (Box 2)
      - Other countries (Box 2)
      - International Liquidity Problem (Box 3)
      - Japan (Box 3)
      - Sterling Crisis, 1964 (Box 3)
      - Chronological press clippings (Box 3)
      - Report of La Previsora Banco Nacional de Crédito, 1962 May (Box 3)
  - Bibliography (Box 3)
  - Basic banking reform file (Box 3)
  - Venezuela Mission, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Puerto Rico, printed reports (Box 3)
  - Congo Beige et Ruandi-Urundi, La Banque Centrale (Belgian Congo), printed reports (Box 3)
  - Triffin Missions, Latin America
    - Interest on Federal Reserve Bank of New York, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Reports, Triffin, 1945, 1945 October (Box 3)
    - South American trip, newspaper clippings, 1946-1947 (Box 3)
    - Chile (Mission), IMF (International Monetary Fund) memo, 1948
      - Triffin notes and charts, 1948 (Box 4)
    - Cuba, financial information, undated (Box 4)
    - Dominican Republic Mission
      - H.C. Wallich and Robert Triffin, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Memos, 1945 (Box 4)
      - Monetary and banking legislation, 1945 (Box 4)
    - Ecuador Mission
      - Balance of payments estimates, IMF Mission, 1946-1947 (Box 4)
      - Central bank policy, 1945, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Central bank reform, memo from Central Bank, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence (1), 1947 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence (2), 1947 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence (3), 1947 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence, duplicates, undated (Box 4)
      - Early memos, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Comments on Fund Mission, 1947
        - IMF, 1947-1948 (Box 4)
      - Emergency Law on International Transfers, text and Triffin comments, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Papers by V.E. Estrada on Equadorian monetary problems and intro-American trade, 1934-1947 (Box 4)
      - Exchange Control, memo and statistics, 1946 (Box 4)
      - Exchange Rares, IMF Mission Memo, 1944, 1947 (Box 4)
      - IMF Staff Memo No. 84 (1) (3 folders), 1947 May (Box 4)
      - IMF Staff Memo No. 84, supplements 1 and 2, 1947 May (Box 4)
      - IMF Staff Memo No. 84, supplement 3 Supplement 3, Rev. 1, 1947 May (Box 4)
      - Inflation and deflation, memos from Central Bank, 1946 (Box 4)
      - Legislation (2 folders), 1947 (Box 4)
      - Letters, 1944 (Box 4)
      - Notes on Central Bank officers, IMF Mission, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Official reports, [1947?] (Box 4)
      - Proposed monetary and banking reforms, IMF memos, 1947 July (Box 4)
      - Fund Mission, statistics, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Proposed monetary and banking laws (text), 1947 (Box 4)
      - Regulation of commerce, memo for Central Bank, 1945, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Report of La Previsora Banco Nacional de Crédito, 1946 (Box 4)
      - Fund Mission, newspaper clipping, 1947 (Box 4)
      - IMF Mission (incomplete), 1947 (Box 4)
      - Economic survey papers, IMF, 1948 (Box 4)
      - Triffin interview with "El Commercio", 1947 (Box 4)
    - Guatemala Mission
      - Central Banking Law, typed text, 1945 (Box 4)
      - Banking laws, texts, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Diagram of Banking System, 1945 (Box 4)
      - "Enters Postwar Period," from Guatemala Time, Inc., 1946 (Box 4)
      - Letters, 1946 (Box 4)
      - Monetary and banking laws, texts and comments, 1946 (Box 4)
      - Monetary and banking reform report, Triffin, 1945 (Box 4)
      - Monetary and banking reform in Guatemala, 1946-1947, undated (Box 5)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1945 (Box 5)
      - Photographs, 1945 (Box 5)
      - Presentation of Central Bank Statistics Memo, [1945?] (Box 5)
      - Progress reports, 1946 (Box 5)
      - Proposed banking legislation text, mimeo, 1946 (Box 5)
      - Proposed monetary legislation and comments, typescript, 1946 (Box 5)
      - Proposed legislation for a Bank for Agriculture and Industry, 1946 March (Box 5)
      - Proposed law for Development Corporation, 1946 May (Box 5)
      - Report, Triffin, 1946 (Box 5)
      - Various statistics, 1946 (Box 5)
    - Haiti Mission
      - Bloch Field Trip, 1950 (Box 5)
    - Honduras
      - Banco Central Como Agente Fiscal del Estado, fourth meeting, Central Bank Exp., 1954 (Box 5)
      - Banking legislation, summary, 1950 (Box 5)
      - Creation and absorption of money, Triffin tables, 1950-1953 (Box 5)
      - Proposed banking law, text, 1953 (Box 5)
    - Panama, Valdes, Manuel M., Panama y su So berania Monetaria, 1951 (Box 5)
    - Paraguay Mission
      - Central Banking Law, 1944 (Box 5)
      - Exchange Control, annual report, 1945 (Box 5)
      - Exchange Regulations, 1945 (Box 5)
      - Photos, 1942 December (Box 5)
      - Proposal for law for new exchange policy, 1945 March (Box 5)
    - Venezuela Mission
      - Estudio sobre la Unificacion Cambiaria, undated (Box 5)
      - Data, 1961 (Box 5)
      - Triffin memoranda, 1961 (Box 5)
      - Triffin tables, 1961 (Box 5)
      - Memos of others, undated (Box 5)
      - Reports on financial conditions, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Triffin Missions to Western Europe
    - Report on France and Belgium, Triffin and Salle, 1948 (Box 6)
    - Report of Mission, IMF Memo, Triffin, 1948 (Box 6)
    - R. Triffin and G. Salle, IMF, 1948 (Box 6)
    - Study of Netherlands Monetary Policy, 1955, undated (Box 6)
  - Triffin Missions to Iran
    - Agrarian Reform, Middle East Journal, [1952?] (Box 6)
    - Bank Melli Balance Sheets, 1951-1953 (Box 6)
    - Banque Melli, Histoire de la, Ahari, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Bank Melli, laws governing, undated (Box 6)
    - Bank Melli Position and Policies, IMF(?), report, 1950 (Box 6)
    - Bank Melli report, 1947-1950 (Box 6)
    - Bank Melli, Statutes of, comment (author?), 1952 (Box 6)
    - Cables and letters, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Development Plan report, 1950-1951 (Box 6)
    - Development Plan, summary and conclusion, 1949 (Box 6)
    - Economic and financial position, E. Erpani, 1952 November (Box 6)
    - Economic proposals by Iranians, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Exchange rates, IMF, 1951 (Box 6)
    - Exchange regulations, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Finance (IBRD?), 1952 (Box 6)
    - Financial position, IMF report, 1949-1953 (Box 6)
    - Financial position and fiscal policy, UN report, 1951 (Box 6)
    - Foreign Trade Trend, comments, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Gutt Mission Report, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Gutt Mission, Report of, 1953 June (Box 6)
    - Gutt, "Les Cocktails,", 1952 (Box 6)
    - Letters, 1952-1953 (Box 6)
    - List of Major UN Documents, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Main Statistical Data, IBRD, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Monetary Situation Statistics, Triffin tables, charts, notes, 1953 (Box 6)
    - Monetary Statistics, Triffin, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Nationalization of Oil, IBRD, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Oil Negotiation, IBRD, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Oil Negotiations, official correspondence, documents, 1951 February-September (Box 6)
    - Organization of Mission to Iran, FAO expert, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Public Administration, U.N. report, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Public Finance, U.N. report (2 folders), 1951 (Box 6)
    - Reports
      - IMF Mission (2 folders), 1952 (Box 6)
      - Middle East Institute, 1951 June (Box 6)
      - Prime Minister, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Review of Economic Conditions in Middle East, U.N. report, 1949-1950 (Box 6)
    - Transportation and Communications, U.N. report, 1950 (Box 6)
    - Triffin correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 6)
    - Triffin memos, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Triffin radio talk, New Haven (2 folders), 1953 (Box 6)
    - Water Resources, U.N. report, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Europe, financial reports
    - Calculated Initial Par Value, Triffin, 1946 (Box 6)
    - La Multilateralisation progressive des devises, Triffin, 1950 (Box 6)
    - Monetary Reconstruction, Triffin, 1952 (Box 6)
    - "Political Crises Delay Monetary Reconstruction," Triffin radio interview (2 folders), 1952 (Box 6)
    - Recent Monetary and Banking Reforms (2 folders), 1945 (Box 6)
    - Belgium
      - Exchange control, Triffin, 1946 (Box 6)
      - Impact of National Banks Transactions on Money Supply, Triffin, IMF (2 folders), 1948 (Box 6)
    - France
      - Current Monetary and Credit Development, notes, Triffin, 1949 (Box 6)
      - Exchange Controls, French proposals re: gold transactions, 1948 (Box 6)
      - Fund's Policy with Respect to Par Value of Franc, Triffin, IMF (2 folders), 1947 (Box 6)
      - Initial Par Values, Triffin, IMF (2 folders), 1946 (Box 6)
      - Readjustment in Exchange Rate Pattern, Triffin (2 folders), 1949 (Box 6)
    - Switzerland
      - Dollar Currency Rates, Triffin, IMF (2 folders), 1947 (Box 6)
  - Latin America, financial reports
    - Bretton Woods Legislation, Triffin, Wallich, and Bourneuf (2 folders), 1945 (Box 6)
    - Central Banking and Monetary Management, Triffin, 1944 (Box 6)
    - Argentina
      - Simplification of Multiple Exchange Rate, Triffin, IMF, 1947 (Box 6)
    - Chile
      - Exchange System, Triffin, IMF (2 folders), 1946 (Box 6)
      - New Chilean Exchange Proposal, Triffin, IMF (2 folders), 1948 (Box 6)
    - Dominican Republic
      - Exchange Rates, Triffin, IMF, 1947 (Box 6)
    - Guatemala
      - Exchange Policy, Triffin, IMF (2 folders), 1947 (Box 6)
      - Initial Par Values, Triffin, IMF (2 folders), 1946 (Box 6)
    - Haiti
      - Tentative Report on Moare's Proposals, Triffin, 1950 (Box 6)
    - Honduras
      - Central Bank, Triffin, 1953 (Box 6)
    - Panama
      - Exchange Rate Situation, Triffin, IMF, 1947 (Box 6)
      - Intitial Par Values, Triffin, IMF, 1946 (Box 6)
      - Notes on Monetary System, Triffin, IMF, 1946 (Box 6)
    - Peru
      - Summary of memos: Peruvian Gold Sales, Triffin, 1946 (Box 6)
    - Uruguay
      - Exchange Control, Triffin, IMF, 1946 (Box 6)
    - Venezuela
      - Multiple Currency Practices, Triffin, IMF (2 folders), 1946 (Box 6)
  - Economic conditions - Europe
    - L'Etalon Monétaire Europeen, Triffin, 1950 (Box 7)
    - Monetary Reconstruction of Europe, Triffin speech, undated (Box 7)
    - Belgium
      - Economic and financial assistance, Triffin, 1945 January-February (Box 7)
    - France
      - Bank Credit and Monetary Stability, first quarter of 1949, Triffin (Box 7)
      - Development in Volume of Money and Credit, Triffin, IMF, 1948 (Box 7)
      - Loan Negotiations, Triffin, 1946 (Box 7)
    - Italy
      - Progress in 1948, Triffin, IMF (2 folders), 1949 (Box 7)
  - Economic conditions - Latin America
    - Recent Monetary and Exchange Developments, Triffin address, 1945 (Box 7)
    - Trade statistics and related correspondence, Triffin, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Balance of payments - Influences of U.S.A.
    - Dimensions and Intractability of Europe Dollar Gap, Triffin, 1953 (Box 7)
  - International Adjustment Exchange rates
    - Simultaneous Exchange Readjustment and Elimination of Controls (2 folders), 1949 (Box 7)
    - Foreign Trade and Finance, Triffin, 1952 (Box 7)
  - International Adjustment - General
    - Intra-European Monetary System: Developments Triffin (2 folders), 1950 (Box 7)
    - La Multilateralization progressives des devises, Triffin (and Eng. Summ.) (2 folders), undated (Box 7)
    - Political Crises Delay Monetary Reconstruction, Triffin interview (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - International Adjustment - Regional Agreements
    - Economic Integration, Triffin (and note by Metzger), 1954 (Box 7)
    - European Payments Union, Triffin, 1951 April (Box 7)
    - European Payments Union, Triffin (2 folders), 1951 May (Box 7)
    - European Payments Union, Triffin, 1951 July (Box 7)
  - Monetary Policy, Theory and Problems
    - Apercu d'histoire économique contemporaine, book review, Triffin, 1950 (Box 7)
    - Monetary Reconstruction of Europe, Triffin, undated (Box 7)
  - Monetary Adjustments (alphabetical by title)
    - Aspects de la réconstruction Monétaire de 1'Europe Triffin, 1954 (Box 7)
    - Intégration et convertibilityé monétaire, Triffin, ECCS (2 folders), 1950 (Box 7)
    - Convertibility, Triffin, 1954 (Box 7)
    - Definition of Par Values, Triffin, 1946 (Box 7)
    - Development of Exchange Control, Policy for IMF, Triffin, 1945 (Box 7)
    - Dollar Gap, Triffin, undated (Box 7)
    - Economic Aspects of the Cross Rate Problem, Triffin, 1947 (Box 7)
    - Economic Aspects of the Cross Rate Problem, Triffin and Bernstein, IMF (2 folders), 1948 (Box 7)
    - Economic Integration, Triffin, 1954 (Box 7)
    - Economic Significance of Multiple Currency Practice, Triffin, IMF (2 folders), 1946 (Box 7)
    - Economic Stability in Changing World: Review, Triffin (2 folders), 1953 (Box 7)
    - EPU and Sterling Convertibility, [1951?] (Box 7)
    - Exchange Control and Equilibrium, Triffin (2 folders), 1948 (Box 7)
    - Excise Taxes vs. Multiple Rates, Triffin (2 folders), 1948 (Box 7)
    - Financement des investissements, Triffin, undated (Box 7)
    - Fundamental Disequilibrium, First Meeting Central Bank Technicians, Triffin, 1947 (Box 7)
    - Historical Function of International Monetary Standard, First Meeting Central Bank Technicians, Triffin (2 folders), 1946 (Box 7)
    - E.E.C. Memo: Elements de Négociation, 1955 (Box 7)
    - International Currency and Reserve Plans, Triffin, 1954 (Box 7)
    - International verses Domestic Money, Triffin (2 folders), 1946 (Box 7)
    - Monetary Policy and International Equilibrium, First Meeting Central Bank Technicians (2 folders), 1946 (Box 7)
    - Multilateralization of Drawing Rights, Triffin, IMF, 1949 (Box 7)
    - New International Monetary Standard, First Meeting Central Bank Technicians, Triffin, 1946 (Box 7)
    - On Presentation of Monetary Statistics, First Meeting Central Bank Technicians, Triffin, 1946 (Box 7)
    - One Europe or Seventeen, Triffin (2 folders), 1952 (Box 7)
    - Papers on Future of Central Banking, Triffin (2 folders), 1945 (Box 7)
    - Political Federation of Europe, Triffin (2 folders), 1952 (Box 7)
    - Postwar Reform of Central Banking, Triffin, 1946 (Box 7)
    - Practical Problem of Exchange Rates: Comments, Triffin, IMF, 1948 (Box 7)
    - Recent European Economic Trends, Ladies Club Speech, Triffin, undated (Box 7)
    - Success Underground, Triffin (2 folders), [1952?] (Box 7)
    - Taxes and Forces Loans on Exchange Transactions, Triffin and Brenner (2 folders), 1947 (Box 7)
  - Europe and Money Muddle, drafts of Sections one, two, three, and conclusion, charts, undated (Box 7)
  - Reprints on economic theory, misc. authors (3 folders) (Box 7)
  - Papers by various friends (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Triffin papers
    - IMF Tables of Reform, 1961 October (Box 8)
    - IMF Reform, 1961 (Box 8)
    - CEA IMF Reform file, 1961 (Box 8)
    - CEA Papers, 1961 (Box 8)
    - CEA, "Unshackling the Monetary System", 1961 (Box 8)
    - Lary Committee on Balance of Payments, 1961 (Box 8)
    - EPC meeting file (2 folders), 1961 (Box 8)
    - OEEC documents for Economic Policy Committee, 1961 April (Box 8)
    - Reprint, Triffin, "The Trade Expansion Act of 1962" (Box 8)
    - Report to the Honorable John F. Kennedy by the Task Force on the Balance of Payments, report, drafts and correspondence, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Kenen, Peter B., Balance of Payments and Economic Policy, 1961 January (Box 8)
    - Documentation on Gold and the Dollar Crisis, 1960
      - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 8)
      - Clippings and printed material, mostly Japanese, 1961 (Box 8)
    - International reserves, Bank for International Settlements, 1962 (Box 8)
    - World reserve tables, gold and dollars, 1949-1953 (Box 8)
  - Council of Economic Advisers, correspondence, 1954 (Box 9)
  - Recession study, IMF, reports, 1953-1954 (Box 9)
  - Randall report, drafts and correspondence (Box 9)
  - Triffin Mission to Japan
    - Printed material, mimeo reports (many in Japanese), 1959-1960 (Box 9)
  - Triffin Mission to Panama
    - Charts, undated (Box 10)
    - Reports (2 folders), 1962 May (Box 10)
    - Printed material, 1959-1961 (Box 10)
    - Economics 182: readings, 1959-1967
      - Balance of payments, undated (Box 10)
      - Student papers, undated (Box 10)
      - First class, Geneva lectures, dissertation topics, 1958-1965 (Box 10)
        See: 189
      - Historical background, pre-1945, dollar shortage, 1958-1969 (Box 10)
      - World liquidity debate, notes, undated (Box 10)
      - Regional integration, printed material, 1964-1965, undated (Box 10)
      - Bretton Woods (includes original correspondence, 1949), 1960-1967, undated (Box 10)
      - Bilateralism, E.P.U. (includes original correspondence, 1950-1951), 1953, undated (Box 10)
    - International Economic Association, meeting, Elsinore, 1959 September (Box 10)
    - Monetary analysis, notes (includes Elsinore material), 1959, undated (Box 10)
    - Gross National Product tables, 1953, undated (Box 10)
    - Current tables, 1966, undated (Box 10)
  - Course papers - Division II, Political Science and Economics (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
  - Writings, speeches and lectures
    - Money and Banking in Chile, Section I, Early History: 1817-1925, typescript, 3 copies, unpublished, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - The Influence of Costs of Production on Fixing of Prices, [post-1958] (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - The Gold Shortage, the Dollar Glut, and the Future of Convertibility, 1959 September (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - The Crisis of the Dollar-Exchange Standard, 1960 November (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Digest of Crucial Statistics on Gold and Dollar Problem, 1960 December (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Brief observations on Dr. Emminger's paper, 1961 January (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - A Simplified Proposal, 1961 April (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Our Participation in the Van Lennep Working Group, 1961 May (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - First Draft Outline of the General Mechanics of a European Reserve Center, 1961 August (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - The Unshackling of the International Monetary System, or Money in Erewhon, 1961 September (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - A Simple Post-Vienna Proposal to Increase the Lending Resources of IMF, 1961 October (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - The Dollar and the International Monetary System, 1962 May (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Shall We Save the Dollar?, 1962 May (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - European Economic Community (EEC) and the Dollar Problem, unpublished paper, 1963 January (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - A.S.A. Gold, the Dollar, Sterling and What Else?, 1965 April (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Conferences
    - Reunion Especial De Bancos Centrales Centro Americanos, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 19-21)
    - Conference on International Monetary Arrangements, Bellagio (Como), 1967 June (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Papers, 1961-1962, 1966, undated (Box 11, Folder 23-25)
    - Zurich Conference, "Adjustment Policies", 1966 (Box 11, Folder 26-27)
    - Zurich Conference, Fritz Machlup, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Princeton and Bellagio, 1964 January (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Princeton and Bellagio, Machlup's study group on international liquidity, 1964-1969 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Papers
    - A Negotiable First Step, 1965 October (Box 12, Folder 3)